Engineering in the U.S. has long been a male-dominated profession.
在美国，工程长期以来一直是男性主导的职业。
Fifty years ago, it looked like that might change.
五十年前，这一局面看起来有可能改变。
In 1970, the percentage of women majoring in engineering was less than 1%.
1970年，主修工程的女性所占比例不到1%。
In 1979, that number was 9%.
1979年，这一数字为9%。
Many hoped women would continue to enter the field at the same rate.
许多人希望女性会继续以同样的速度进入这一领域。
But that’s not what happened.
但事情并没有这样发展。
Today, only 21% of engineering majors are women, a number largely unchanged since 2000.
如今，工程专业的学生中只有21%是女性，这一数字自2000年以来基本没有变化。
I am a historian who, along with my colleagues, surveyed 251 women engineers who graduated from college in the 1970s.
我是一名历史学家，曾与同事一道调查了251位20世纪70年代大学毕业的女工程师。
These pioneers reflected on the challenges they faced—and had advice for women entering the field today.
这些先驱回顾了她们当年面临的种种挑战，也为如今进入这一领域的女性提出了建议。
One survey taker explained, “The greatest challenge for me was continuing to believe in myself, when all the messages I was getting were that I would never be taken seriously or promoted or given raises at the same rate as men, who were clearly less qualified and not as smart as I was.”
一位受访者解释说：“对我来说，最大的挑战是坚持相信自己，可当时我得到的所有信息都在告诉我：我永远不会被认真对待，也不会和男性以同样的速度获得晋升或加薪，而那些男性显然资质不如我，也没有我聪明。”
A chemical engineer who worked in manufacturing agreed, “You have to prove yourself just because you are female.
一位在制造业工作的化学工程师也表示赞同：“就因为你是女性，你就得证明自己。
And you have to work twice as hard!”
而且你还得加倍努力！”
A civil engineer said, “We are ‘women engineers.’
一位土木工程师说：“我们是‘女工程师’。
People don’t refer to a man as a ‘man engineer’—he’s an engineer.
人们不会把男性称为‘男工程师’——他就是工程师。
We are constantly reminded that we don’t truly belong.”
我们不断被提醒：自己并不真正属于这里。”
Another civil engineer stated, “On many levels, you’re never quite one of the group.”
另一位土木工程师表示：“从很多层面来说，你始终不完全算是这个群体中的一员。”
Women also talked about family caregiving responsibilities.
这些女性还谈到了照料家人的责任。
A retired vice president from a major chemical company stated, “Young women engineers are on an equal footing until they have children; then they struggle to balance work and family—and compete with men who don’t have the same household responsibilities.”
一家大型化工公司的退休副总裁表示：“年轻女工程师在生孩子之前都处于平等的地位；有了孩子之后，她们就要艰难地兼顾工作与家庭——还要与那些没有同样家庭责任的男性竞争。”
But over the years things have changed a lot.
但多年来，情况已经发生了很大变化。
Young women engineers are more accepted mostly because there are just more of them.
年轻女工程师更受接纳，主要就是因为她们的人数多了。
Many women engineers hailed the benefits of their chosen career.
许多女工程师都盛赞了自己所选职业的种种好处。
A program manager in manufacturing stated that engineering is the best degree.
一位在制造业工作的项目经理表示，工程学位是最好的学位。
A mechanical engineer said, “It will give you the flexibility to do almost anything.
一位机械工程师说：“它会给你灵活选择的余地，让你几乎什么事都能做。
It is also satisfying to see the effects of what you have done.”
看到自己所做的事产生效果，也让人很满足。”